<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./_c74_ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="the.cache" module="max" category="Data">

	<digest>
		View and empty a Max application's cache folder
	</digest>

	<description>
		Written by Tim Heinze © 2020, www.xenorama.com. <br/>
		View and delete any unwanted files from Max' cache folder. When used in an executable/standalone requires the application's name as argument or symbol in rightmost inlet.
	</description>

	<discussion>
	</discussion>

	<!--METADATA (REMOVE FOR SIMPLICITY) -->
	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Tim Heinze</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Xenorama</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Max</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Data</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<!--INLETS (REMOVE FOR SIMPLICITY) -->

	<!--OUTLETS (REMOVE FOR SIMPLICITY) -->

	<!--ARGUMENTS-->
	<objarglist>
		<objarg name="standalone-name" optional="1" type="symbol" size="1">
			<digest>
				Name of standalone application
			</digest>
			<description>
				Name of standalone application. By default, <o>the.cache</o> manages the cache folder of the Max application (default: <m>Max 8</m>). An additional symbol can be provided to manage the cache folder of the Max standalone by the same name instead.
			</description>
		</objarg>
	</objarglist>

	<!--ATTRIBUTES (REMOVE FOR SIMPLICITY) -->
	<attributelist>
	<attribute name="types" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1">
		<digest>
			Specify file types to filter
		</digest>
		<description>
			Specify file types to filter. See the <m>gettypes</m> method to post supported filetype-nomenclature to the Max window or check the <o>folder</o> helpfile.
			<br/>
			The default is <m>types</m> without any argument, listing and managing all files.
		</description>
	</attribute>
		<attribute name="post" get="1" set="1" type="list" size="1">
		<digest>
			Post executed commands to Max Window
		</digest>
		<description>
			Post executed commands to Max Window (default: 1). When disabled, the user will not be notified about cleared files, however, the abstraction is based around <o>node.script</o> which posts its file handling steps to the console.
		</description>
	</attribute>
</attributelist>

	<!--MESSAGES-->

	<methodlist>
		<method name="bang">
			<arglist>
			</arglist>
			<digest>
				Populate attached menu with cache files
			</digest>
			<description>
				Populate attached menu with cache files. If a <o>umenu</o> or <o>chooser</o> is connected to the middle outlet of <o>the.cache</o>, sending <m>bang</m> to the first inlet will populate the menu with all files in the cache folder specified by the <at>types</at> attribute.
				<br/>
				The menu entries can be used to manually remove single files using the <m>remove</m> method.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="empty">
			<arglist>
			</arglist>
			<digest>
				Will delete all files from the cache folder
			</digest>
			<description>
				Will delete all files from the cache folder of the specified filetype.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="reveal">
			<arglist>
			</arglist>
			<digest>
				Open and view the cache folder
			</digest>
			<description>
				The word <m>reveal</m> Will launch the filebrowser and open the cahce folder.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="remove">
			<arglist>
			</arglist>
			<digest>
				Delete single files from cache folder
			</digest>
			<description>
				Delete single files from cache folder. Only the filename is required, not the entire filepath since it is assumed we are targeting the cache folder.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="gettypes">
			<arglist>
			</arglist>
			<digest>
				Post supported filetypes to the max console
			</digest>
			<description>
				Post supported filetypes to the max console. The match those filetypes supported by the <o>fodler</o> object. Any of the listed filetypes can be specified using the <at>types</at> attribute.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

	<!--EXAMPLE-->

	<!--SEEALSO (REMOVE FOR SIMPLICITY) -->
	<seealsolist>
	</seealsolist>

</c74object>
